# Francisco Martínez.

# **Technical Writer**

Senior Technical Writer with over 23 years of experience and more than 16 years in writing and developing technical publications. Seeking work opportunities to further enhance my skills as a Technical Writer.

I'm also open to freelance writing and editing work.

❖ Efficiency☒ Goals☒ End result of docs

✓ Accomplishments

Contact

Seville (Spain)

@ Send a mail in LinkedIn

**G** GitHub

**৺** Twitter

## **Experience**

#### Tech Mahindra | TECHNICAL WRITER

Airbus L&M Programs Maintenance Docs TID Support

ijuly 2017 - Present | Seville, Spain (Hybrid)

#### Quest Global | TECHNICAL WRITER

Airbus MRTT Catalog & Structure Manual Responsible

october 2006 - june 2017 | Seville, Spain

#### Abengoa | Senior Project Designer

ioctober 2005 - october 2006 | Seville, Spain

#### Hidral | Senior Project Designer

ijune 2005 - october 2005 | Seville, Spain

## Auxiple Outsourcing | Airbus A380 Technical

Illustrator

idecember 2004 - june 2005 | 🏶 Seville, Spain

#### Tecnocontrol | Senior Designer

iseptember 2004 - december 2004 | Seville, Spain

#### Dinotec Industrial Draftsman

ijune 2004 - september 2004 | Seville, Spain

#### Nilo - Aqualia | Industrial Draftsman

🚞 october 2000 - june 2004 | 🏶 Seville, Spain

### **Education**

#### FPII Industrial Design (Higher National Diploma)

Polytechnic Institute of Seville

iseptember 1998 - june 2001 | Seville, Spain

## Languages

English: Full Professional Proficiency (B2)

Spanish: Fluent (Native)

#### Courses

#### **IT Courses:**

100% Responsive Web Design (HTML, CCS). freeCodeCamp Certification.

70% Scientific Computing with Python. freeCodeCamp Certification.

50% JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures. freeCodeCamp Certification.

**100%** Automation Engineer Certification: Maven-Jenkins-Selenium.TM Certificate.

100% Agile: Scrum Management. TM Certificate.

100% VBA and VBScript. TM Certificate.

#### TW and Design Courses:

100% Aircraft Systems Course: Electrical and Avionics.

100% Introduction to Aeronautical Systems: Hydraulic and Pneumatic.

100% CAD Specialist.

100% Mechanical Design with CATIA V5.

100% Office Business Management (MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint).

#### **Languages Courses:**

**100%** English Course Upper Intermediate (B2) Semi-Intensive.

100% English Course Intermediate (B1-B2).

100% English Pre-Intermediate level (A2).

100% Simplified Technical English (ASD-STE100 v4).

Markup Languages	TW Tools	lechnical Writing
XML	Arbortex	Wrinting
90%	90%	90%
HTML	Oxigen XML Editor	Translation
80%	50%	70%
CSS	MKDocs	Al tools
70%	80%	60%
Markdown	ULM Lucidchart	SEO
95%	50%	60%
reStructuredText	GitHub	
75%	40%	Specs
	Confluence	S1000D
Code	30%	90%
Python	IETP/IETM	DITA
60%	95%	60%
Javascript		Microsoft Writing Style Guide
45%	App & CMS	60%
SQL	MS Office & G Docs	ASD-STE100
30%	80%	85%
JSON	Adobe	
60%	65%	Spoken languages
VB Script	Wordpress	Spanish
75%	75%	100%
Selenium IDE	Sensei LMS	English
45%	45%	70%

## **Relevant Skills and Achievements**

- EDocumentation end-user oriented and visual communication.
- Research skills, audience analysis and quality assurance.
- Helped clients in developing a complete knowledge base for their products.
- ☑ Increased end-user satisfaction and received excellent feedback for complex documentation.
- Writing documentation on thousands of topics, such as troubleshooting, standard procedures and functional specifications.